Colin White

847-828-3885 1099 Folsom Street San Francisco, CA 94103

colin@abacus.ai https://crwhite.ml

Research Interests My work spans machine learning and theoretical computer science. I am particularly interested in automated machine learning (AutoML) and neural architecture search (NAS), both in designing new methods and in steering the field to give reproducible, fair comparisons between methods.

EXPERIENCE

Abacus.AI, San Francisco, CA

Head of Research Oct. 2020 - Present Research Scientist May 2019 - Oct. 2020

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D. in Computer Science Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2018

Advisor: Maria-Florina Balcan

Thesis: New Aspects of Beyond Worst-Case Analysis

Amherst College, Amherst, MA

B.A. in Computer Science and Mathematics Sep. 2010 - May 2014

Cumulative GPA: 3.76/4.0, Computer Science GPA: 3.96/4.0, Mathematics GPA: 3.95/4.0

Advisor: Lyle McGeoch

Thesis: Lower Bounds on the Runtime of Routing Algorithms for Graphs of Low Highway Dimension

Honors AND AWARDS Top 10% of reviewers at NeurIPS 2020 Sep. 2020 Top 50% of reviewers at NeurIPS 2019 Sep. 2019 NDSEG Fellowship Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2018 NeurIPS Student Travel Grant Dec. 2018 Amherst Memorial Fellowship Sep. 2016 - Aug. 2017 Sep. 2016 - Aug. 2017 CMU Graduate Student Association/Provost Student Travel Grant Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) Student Travel Grant May 2017 Heidelberg Laureate Forum, invited as a Young Researcher Sep. 2017 Sep. 2014 - Aug. 2016 John Woodruff Simpson Fellowship Sep. 2014

Post-Baccalaureate Summer Research Fellowship, Amherst College Computer Science Prize, Amherst College Summa Cum Laude, Amherst College

May 2014 May 2014

Henry F. Dunbar Award, Amherst College Swimming and Diving Team

May 2014

Preprints

"Local Search is State of the Art for Neural Architecture Search Benchmarks."

C. White, S. Nolen, Y. Savani.

In submission, 2020.

Journal PUBLICATIONS "k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience."

With M. Balcan and N. Haghtalab.

Transactions on Algorithms Journal (TALG) 2020.

"Small dynamical heights for quadratic polynomials and rational functions."

With R. Benedetto, R. Chen, T. Hyde, and Y. Kovacheva.

Experimental Mathematics, 2014.

Conference

"BANANAS: Bayesian Optimization with Neural Architectures for Neural Architecture Search."

PUBLICATIONS C. White, W. Neiswanger, Y. Savani.

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021.

"A Study on Encodings for Neural Architecture Search."

C. White, W. Neiswanger, S. Nolen, Y. Savani.

Selected for spotlight presentation.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.

"Intra-Processing Methods for Debiasing Neural Networks."

Y. Savani, C. White, N. Govindarajulu.

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.

"Robust Communication-Optimal Distributed Clustering Algorithms."

With P. Awasthi, A. Bakshi, M. Balcan, and D. Woodruff.

International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP) 2019.

"Data-Driven Clustering via Parameterized Lloyd's Families."

With M. Balcan and T. Dick.

Selected for spotlight presentation.

Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2018.

"Learning-Theoretic Foundations of Algorithm Configuration for Combinatorial Partitioning Problems"

With M. Balcan, V. Nagarajan, and E. Vitercik.

Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) 2017.

"Data Driven Resource Allocation for Distributed Learning."

With T. Dick, M. Li, V. Pillutla, M. Balcan, and A. Smola.

International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS) 2017.

"Learning Combinatorial Functions from Pairwise Comparisons."

With M. Balcan and E. Vitercik.

Conference on Learning Theory (COLT) 2016.

"k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience."

With M. Balcan and N. Haghtalab.

International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP) 2016.

"Lower Bounds in the Preprocessing and Query Phases of Routing Algorithms."

C White

European Symposium on Algorithms (ESA) 2015.

Theses "New Aspects of Beyond Worst-Case Analysis."

C. White.

Ph.D. Thesis, Carnegie Mellon University, 2018.

"Lower Bounds in the Preprocessing and Query Phases of Routing Algorithms."

C. White.

Undergraduate Thesis, Amherst College, 2014.

WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS "A Study on Encodings for Neural Architecture Search."

C. White, W. Neiswanger, S. Nolen, Y. Savani.

ICML Workshop on AutoML, 2020.

"Local Search is State of the Art for Neural Architecture Search Benchmarks."

C. White, S. Nolen, Y. Savani.

ICML Workshop on AutoML, 2020.

"Neural Architecture Search via Bayesian Optimization with a Neural Network Prior."

C. White, W. Neiswanger, Y. Savani.

NeurIPS Workshop on Meta Learning, 2019.

"Deep Uncertainty Estimation for Model-based Neural Architecture Search."

C. White, W. Neiswanger, Y. Savani.

NeurIPS Workshop on Bayesian Deep Learning, 2019.

"DECO: Debiasing through Compositional Optimization of Machine Learning Models."

N. Govindarajulu, <u>C. White</u>.

NeurIPS Workshop on Robust AI in Financial Services, 2019.

"Differentiable Functions for Combining First-order Constraints with Deep Learning via Weighted Proof Tracing."

N. Govindarajulu, <u>C. White</u>.

NeurIPS Workshop on Knowledge Representation to ML, 2019.

"Data Driven Resource Allocation for Distributed Learning."

With T. Dick, M. Li, V. Pillutla, M. Balcan, and A. Smola.

AAAI Workshop on Distributed Machine Learning, 2019.

"An Improved Parallel Iterative Algorithm for Stable Matching."

C. White, E. Lu.

SuperComputing Student Poster Session, 2013.

Talks	Bananas, Encodings, and Local Search: Insights into Neural Architecture Search AutoML Seminar, ELLIS Berlin and Freiburg, Germany (virtual).	Nov. 2020
	An Introduction to Neural Architecture Search. Abacus.AI webinar. Abacus.AI workshop. AICamp webinar.	Oct. 2020 Dec. 2019 Jul. 2019
	Data-Driven Clustering via Parameterized Lloyd's Families. Automated Algorithms Seminar at CMU.	May 2018
	Robust Communication-Optimal Distributed Clustering Algorithms. Theory Lunch Seminar at CMU.	Apr. 2017
	k-center Clustering under Perturbation Resilience. Simons Institute BWCA Workshop. Theory Lunch Seminar at CMU. Dagstuhl Workshop on Learning Theory. Machine Learning Dept. Journal Club Class at CMU.	Nov. 2016 Sep. 2016 Aug. 2015 Sep. 2016
SERVICE	Program Committee Member for ICML, UAI, AAAI Reviewer for JMLR, Algorithmica, TALG, TPAMI, NeurIPS, ICML, AISTATS, AAAI, UAI, FOCS, STOC, ITCS	$2016,2019,2020 \\ 2015-2020$
	Doctoral Review Committee Member, CMU A panel of graduate students and faculty who oversee the Ph.D. program	2015 - 2018
	FreeCSD, a social organization for the Ph.D. department at CMU	2015 - 2018
	Theory Lunch Organizer, CMU	2016
	Ph.D. Admitted Students Open House Organizer, CMU	2016

OTHER INTERESTS Rock climbing, distance running